
Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 36176328,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 9,
      day 30,
      hour 2,
      minute 25
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "NMDAR autoantibodies in psychiatric disease - An
 immunopsychiatric continuum and potential predisposition for disease
 pathogenesis."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Hansen N",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University
 Medical Center Gottingen, Gottingen, Germany.; Translational
 Psychoneuroscience, University Medical Center Gottingen, Gottingen, Germany."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "J Transl Autoimmun",
          ml-jta "J Transl Autoimmun",
          issn "2589-9090",
          name "Journal of translational autoimmunity"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 9,
            day 21
          },
          volume "5",
          pages "100165",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 8,
                day 21
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 20
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 21
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 30,
                hour 2,
                minute 25
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 10,
                day 1,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 10,
                day 1,
                hour 6,
                minute 1
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 36176328,
        doi "10.1016/j.jtauto.2022.100165",
        pii "S2589-9090(22)00026-0",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC9513762"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.jtauto.2022.100165"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "N-Methyl-d-Aspartate-receptor (NMDAR) antibody encephalitis is a
 disease discovered two decades ago. Our knowledge about it has recently
 deepened dramatically. However, the significance of NMDAR antibodies in
 psychiatric disease cannot be determined if there are no clear indications of
 brain inflammation or an autoimmune encephalitis mediated by NMDAR
 antibodies. Furthermore, the long-term interaction and connection between
 these two disease entities are unclear. In this paper we aim to elucidate the
 relationship between these disease entities. We propose two distinct models
 that explain the on the one hand a condition in which a minor inflammatory
 state as in psychiatric disease culminates in a severe state of inflammation
 characterized by NMDAR encephalitis. On the other hand, we postulate a model
 in which an NMDAR encephalitis might later create favorable conditions for
 inducing psychiatric disease. These models should be kept in mind for further
 investigations examining the long-term outcome of NMDAR autoantibody immunity
 in the brain and its functions.",
    pmid 36176328,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Review"
    },
    status premedline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 36174451,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 9,
      day 29,
      hour 18,
      minute 29
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Cancer activates microglia to the same extent as chronic stress
 throughout stress neurocircuitry in a mouse model of breast cancer."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "McCaffrey D",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia; Discipline of Psychiatry and
 Mental Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of New South Wales, Sydney,
 Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Lawther AJ",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Weickert CS",
            affil str "Discipline of Psychiatry and Mental Health, Faculty of
 Medicine, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; Schizophrenia
 Research Laboratory, Neuroscience Research Australia, Randwick, New South
 Wales, Australia; Department of Neuroscience & Physiology, Upstate Medical
 University, Syracuse, NY, USA."
          },
          {
            name ml "Walker AK",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia; Discipline of Psychiatry and
 Mental Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of New South Wales, Sydney,
 Australia; Drug Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of Pharmaceutical
 Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, Australia. Electronic address:
 a.walker@neura.edu.au."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Psychoneuroendocrinology",
          ml-jta "Psychoneuroendocrinology",
          issn "1873-3360",
          name "Psychoneuroendocrinology"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 9,
            day 21
          },
          volume "146",
          pages "105938",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus aheadofprint,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 6,
                day 7
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 10
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 19
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 30,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 30,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 29,
                hour 18,
                minute 29
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 36174451,
        pii "S0306-4530(22)00279-7",
        doi "10.1016/j.psyneuen.2022.105938",
        other {
          db "ELocationID pii",
          tag str "S0306-4530(22)00279-7"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.psyneuen.2022.105938"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "The prevalence of stress-related comorbidities is increased
 approximately 3-fold in cancer patients compared to the general population.
 There is a scarcity of research focusing on the biological brain changes
 caused by the cancer due to the assumption that psychological symptoms are
 solely caused by the stress of a cancer diagnosis. Recent clinical evidence
 indicates that declines in cognition and increases in mood symptoms occur
 prior to an individual receiving a cancer diagnosis, suggesting that the
 cancer itself may play a role in mediating biological brain change.
 Furthermore, the presence of a tumour may change the brain response to
 environmental stressors unrelated to a cancer diagnosis. Using a syngeneic,
 orthotopic mouse model of breast cancer, we compared the impact of mammary
 tumours and chronic restraint stress on microglial and astrocytic activation
 throughout stress-relevant neurocircuitry. We also examined whether changes
 in microglial and astrocytic activation overlapped with changes in chronic
 neuronal activity. We show that cancer and chronic restraint stress activates
 microglia to the same magnitude in the same subcortical brain regions, and
 that this activation correlates with stress coping behaviours. The findings
 suggest that in some cancer patients, microglia may be activated in brain
 regions involved in interpreting and responding to psychological distress
 before they are aware of their diagnosis. In contrast, cancer reduced
 astrocyte reactivity in two cortical brain regions where there were no clear
 changes in response to chronic restraint stress. Taken together, it is likely
 that interventions that aim to improve anxiety and stress in cancer patients
 by targeting glial responses to cancer would need to be cell-specific;
 reducing microglial activation and/or stimulating astrocytic activation.",
    pmid 36174451,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status publisher
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 36170741,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 9,
      day 28,
      hour 17,
      minute 32
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Immunopsychiatry of Infected Ears, Sinuses, Skulls, and
 Meninges: Mast Cells, Mozart, Van Gogh."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Treviranus GRS",
            affil str "BipoSuisse - Psychiatrische Praxis, Vereinsweg 11, CH
 3012 Berne, Switzerland, biposuisse@bluewin.ch."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Psychiatr Danub",
          ml-jta "Psychiatr Danub",
          issn "0353-5053",
          name "Psychiatria Danubina"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 9
          },
          volume "34",
          issue "Suppl 8",
          pages "265-275",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 28,
                hour 17,
                minute 32
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 29,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 10,
                day 1,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 36170741
      }
    },
    abstract "Medical psychiatry acquires more prominence in the biological
 field by new anatomical insights into the wrappings of the brain: meninges,
 but also Meningo-Calvarial Channels (MCCs) connecting the former with the
 bone marrows' also neuronally steered, functions. The skull-bone's meningeal
 arteries through migrating and orchestrating mast cells within a framework
 stressing their relations with arteries (Treviranus 2012-21) could explain
 enigmatic phenomena like migrainous and post-injury Cortical Spreading
 Depressions (CSD) or the Reversible Cerebral Vasoconstriction Syndrome (RCVS)
 escalating to ""PRES"". The skull might be accessed along chronic
 (para-)infectious paths resulting in Skull Bone Osteomyelitis (SBO) from the
 ear-nose-throat, dental and other microbiomes. Such paths seem promoted by
 compromised innate immune defenses: by ""Mendelian"" susceptibility, and/or
 acquired anti-INF-gamma- or other auto-immunity or various microbial ""Trojan
s"" of e. g. meningeal myelo- and lymphocytes. These interact e. g. from the
 calvarial marrow niches onward. Hereby competing local and ""intentional""
 intruding mast cells - by disturbing (or ingeniously boosting) cortical
 development and functioning - acquire relevance by interacting with arteries
 (Treviranus 2018, 2021). This predicts findings in behavior (Fitzpatrick &
 Morrow 2017) an ""aortal"" arterial biomechanical foundation of
 parasympathetic reverse arterio-intramural cerebro-interstitial drainage by
 CIMURAF/IPAD-2.0 (Treviranus 2018-21). Here the recent physiological
 re-conceptions of the skull illuminate own case histories through a gamut of
 possibly relevant neuro(-surgico)-psychiatric challenges. Among these
 meningo-cerebral immune, vasospastic, and cystic processes some generate
 broad ""experiential"" hallucinations, which may slowly transit to true
 psychoses through ""perfect crime lesions"" of neurons and glia by
 tryptase-armed mast cells descending into parenchyma often congested by ""pus
h-back"". These emerging hypotheses coalesce in advancing an integrative
 macro-medical psychiatry and even the pathography of Van Gogh and Mozart
 stressing the benign and creative roles of mast cells.",
    mesh {
      {
        term "Head"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Mast Cells"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Meninges"
      },
      {
        term "Skull"
      },
      {
        term "Tryptases"
      }
    },
    substance {
      {
        type ec,
        cit "3.4.21.59",
        name "Tryptases"
      }
    },
    pmid 36170741,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 36054787,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 9,
      day 2,
      hour 15,
      minute 14
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Dietary intake in children on the autism spectrum is altered and
 linked to differences in autistic traits and sensory processing styles."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Mathew NE",
            affil str "Discipline of Paediatrics & Child Health, School of
 Clinical Medicine, UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales,
 Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.; Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry,
 Neuroscience Research Australia, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Mallitt KA",
            affil str "Sydney School of Public Health, Faculty of Medicine and
 Health, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.; Discipline
 of Psychiatry and Mental Health, School of Clinical Medicine, UNSW Medicine
 and Health, University of New South Wales, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Masi A",
            affil str "Discipline of Psychiatry and Mental Health, School of
 Clinical Medicine, UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales,
 Sydney, New South Wales, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Katz T",
            affil str "Discipline of Paediatrics & Child Health, School of
 Clinical Medicine, UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales,
 Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.; Department of Nutrition and Dietetics,
 Sydney Children's Hospital, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Walker AK",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.; Discipline of Psychiatry and
 Mental Health, School of Clinical Medicine, UNSW Medicine and Health,
 University of New South Wales, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.; Drug
 Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash
 University, Parkville, Victoria, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Morris MJ",
            affil str "School of Medical Sciences, University of New South
 Wales, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Ooi CY",
            affil str "Discipline of Paediatrics & Child Health, School of
 Clinical Medicine, UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales,
 Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.; Department of Gastroenterology, Sydney
 Children's Hospital, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Autism Res",
          ml-jta "Autism Res",
          issn "1939-3806",
          name "Autism research : official journal of the International
 Society for Autism Research"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 8,
            day 26
          },
          language "eng",
          pubstatus aheadofprint,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 3
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 8,
                day 10
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 3,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 3,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 9,
                day 2,
                hour 15,
                minute 14
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 36054787,
        doi "10.1002/aur.2798",
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1002/aur.2798"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Diets of children and adolescents on the autism spectrum often
 differ when compared to their non-autistic peers. Most dietary studies have
 been limited by small sample sizes and rarely assess the heterogeneity of
 autism. Addressing this gap, this study compared the anthropometrics, dietary
 composition, dietary quality, and food variety of 154 Australian children and
 adolescents on the spectrum and 213 non-autistic children (71 siblings and
 142 unrelated controls). Beyond the case-control approach, within-group
 comparisons assessed the influence of autism clinical presentations and
 sensory processing styles on body mass index (BMI) and measures of dietary
 intake among those on the spectrum. In this word first study of diet that
 included between-group comparisons with non-autistic peers (siblings and an
 unrelated comparison group) and within-autism group comparisons, we found
 that children on the spectrum consumed limited variety and lower quality of
 food and non-autistic siblings also ate comparably higher levels of
 energy-dense, nutrient poor food, and less diary. This may be due to autistic
 traits influencing family's diets or shared sensory sensitivities driving
 dietary intake. Within the autism group, higher autistic traits were
 associated with lower BMIs and a specific dietary pattern higher in simple
 carbohydrates and lower in unprocessed protein. Contrastingly, greater
 sensitivity to sensory stimuli was associated with a healthier diet.
 Increased age was linked to more varied diets but also diets higher in
 saturated fats and energy-dense, nutrient poor foods. Overall, this research
 highlights that potential mediators of dietary intake, such as familial
 influences, autistic traits, sensory processing styles, age and sex, need to
 be considered when assessing diet in the autistic population. LAY SUMMARY: In
 this study of dietary differences linked to autism, children, and teenagers
 on the spectrum ate fewer different foods and were less likely to eat
 recommended amounts of fruits and vegetables when compared to non-autistic
 siblings and unrelated children and teenagers. There were also family
 differences, in that those on the spectrum and their siblings ate more
 unhealthy foods and less dairy. Among those on the spectrum, dietary
 differences were linked to age, sex, autistic traits and sensory processing
 styles.",
    idnum {
      "Australian Government Department of Education, Skills and Employment
 Research Training Program",
      "GXX0049/Neuroscience Research Australia",
      "PS56837/Sydney Partnership for Health Education Research and Enterprise",
      "O200005/Sydney Partnership for Health Education Research and Enterprise",
      "APP1194358/National Health and Medical Research Council"
    },
    pmid 36054787,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status publisher
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35711412,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 6,
      day 17,
      hour 2,
      minute 27
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Immunopsychiatry - Innovative Technology to Characterize Disease
 Activity in Autoantibody-Associated Psychiatric Diseases."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Hansen N",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University
 Medical Center Gottingen, Gottingen, Germany.; Translational
 Psychoneuroscience, University Medical Center Gottingen, Gottingen, Germany."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Front Immunol",
          ml-jta "Front Immunol",
          issn "1664-3224",
          name "Frontiers in immunology"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 5,
            day 23
          },
          volume "13",
          pages "867229",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 31
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 19
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 6,
                day 17,
                hour 2,
                minute 27
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 6,
                day 18,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 6,
                day 22,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35711412,
        doi "10.3389/fimmu.2022.867229",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC9197207"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.3389/fimmu.2022.867229"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Background: Anti-neural autoantibody-associated psychiatric
 disease is a novel field in immunopsychiatry that has been attracting
 attention thanks to its potentially positive therapeutic outcome and distinct
 prognosis compared with non-organic psychiatric disease. This review aims to
 describe recent novel technological developments for improving diagnostics in
 the field of autoantibody-related psychiatric disease. Methods: We screened
 for relevant articles in PubMed for this narrative article. We focused on
 research methods such as neuroimaging, immune cells and inflammation markers,
 and molecular biomarkers in human biofluids like serum and cerebrospinal
 fluid and plasma proteomics. Results: We introduce several novel methods for
 investigating autoinflammation with the aim of optimizing therapies for
 autoantibody-associated psychiatric disease. We describe measuring the
 translocator protein 18kDa in activated microglia via positron emission
 tomography imaging, brain volumetric assessment, flow cell cytometry of
 cerebrospinal fluid and blood, and blood biological probes as well as
 psychopathological cues to help us gain insights into diagnosing inflammation
 and brain damage better in psychiatric patients presenting a suspected
 autoimmune etiology. Conclusion: Our short methodological review provides an
 overview of recent developments in the field of autoantibody-related
 immunopsychiatry. More research is needed to prove their usefulness in
 diagnosing and treating autoantibody-associated psychiatric disease and its
 subtypes.",
    mesh {
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Autoantibodies"
      },
      {
        term "Biomarkers"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        term "Inflammation"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Mental Disorders",
        qual {
          {
            subh "diagnosis"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Technology"
      }
    },
    substance {
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Autoantibodies"
      },
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Biomarkers"
      }
    },
    pmid 35711412,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Review",
      "Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35492247,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 5,
      day 2,
      hour 6,
      minute 8
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Autoantibodies against NCAM1 from patients with schizophrenia
 cause schizophrenia-related behavior and changes in synapses in mice."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Shiwaku H",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Tokyo
 Medical and Dental University Graduate School, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Katayama S",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Tokyo
 Medical and Dental University Graduate School, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Kondo K",
            affil str "Department of Neuropathology, Medical Research
 Institute and Center for Brain Integration Research, Tokyo Medical and Dental
 University, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Nakano Y",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Tokyo
 Medical and Dental University Graduate School, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Tanaka H",
            affil str "Department of Neuropathology, Medical Research
 Institute and Center for Brain Integration Research, Tokyo Medical and Dental
 University, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Yoshioka Y",
            affil str "Department of Neuropathology, Medical Research
 Institute and Center for Brain Integration Research, Tokyo Medical and Dental
 University, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Fujita K",
            affil str "Department of Neuropathology, Medical Research
 Institute and Center for Brain Integration Research, Tokyo Medical and Dental
 University, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Tamaki H",
            affil str "Department of Neurology and Neurological Science, Tokyo
 Medical and Dental University Graduate School, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Takebayashi H",
            affil str "Kurita Hospital, Kanagawa 212-0054, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Terasaki O",
            affil str "Kurita Hospital, Kanagawa 212-0054, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Nagase Y",
            affil str "Takatsuki Hospital, Tokyo 192-0005, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Nagase T",
            affil str "Takatsuki Hospital, Tokyo 192-0005, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Kubota T",
            affil str "Department of Medical Technology, Tsukuba International
 University, Ibaraki 300-0051, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Ishikawa K",
            affil str "The Center for Personalized Medicine for Healthy Aging,
 Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Okazawa H",
            affil str "Department of Neuropathology, Medical Research
 Institute and Center for Brain Integration Research, Tokyo Medical and Dental
 University, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          },
          {
            name ml "Takahashi H",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Tokyo
 Medical and Dental University Graduate School, Tokyo 113-8510, Japan."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Cell Rep Med",
          ml-jta "Cell Rep Med",
          issn "2666-3791",
          name "Cell reports. Medicine"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 4,
            day 19
          },
          volume "3",
          issue "4",
          pages "100597",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 4
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 31
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 3,
                day 14
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 5,
                day 2,
                hour 6,
                minute 8
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 5,
                day 3,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 5,
                day 4,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35492247,
        doi "10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100597",
        pii "S2666-3791(22)00114-8",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC9043990"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100597"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "From genetic and etiological studies, autoimmune mechanisms
 underlying schizophrenia are suspected; however, the details remain unclear.
 In this study, we describe autoantibodies against neural cell adhesion
 molecule (NCAM1) in patients with schizophrenia (5.4%, cell-based assay;
 6.7%, ELISA) in a Japanese cohort (n = 223). Anti-NCAM1 autoantibody disrupts
 both NCAM1-NCAM1 and NCAM1-glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor (GDNF)
 interactions. Furthermore, the anti-NCAM1 antibody purified from patients
 with schizophrenia interrupts NCAM1-Fyn interaction and inhibits
 phosphorylation of FAK, MEK1, and ERK1 when introduced into the cerebrospinal
 fluid of mice and also reduces the number of spines and synapses in frontal
 cortex. In addition, it induces schizophrenia-related behavior in mice,
 including deficient pre-pulse inhibition and cognitive impairment. In
 conclusion, anti-NCAM1 autoantibodies in patients with schizophrenia cause
 schizophrenia-related behavior and changes in synapses in mice. These
 antibodies may be a potential therapeutic target and serve as a biomarker to
 distinguish a small but treatable subgroup in heterogeneous patients with
 schizophrenia.",
    mesh {
      {
        term "Autoantibodies"
      },
      {
        term "CD56 Antigen",
        qual {
          {
            subh "genetics"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Neural Cell Adhesion Molecules",
        qual {
          {
            subh "genetics"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Schizophrenia",
        qual {
          {
            subh "genetics"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Synapses",
        qual {
          {
            subh "metabolism"
          }
        }
      }
    },
    substance {
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Autoantibodies"
      },
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "CD56 Antigen"
      },
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "NCAM1 protein, human"
      },
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Neural Cell Adhesion Molecules"
      }
    },
    pmid 35492247,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35452794,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 4,
      day 22,
      hour 20,
      minute 10
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Interleukin-6 receptor antagonists in immunopsychiatry: Can they
 lead to increased interleukin-6 in the central nervous system (CNS) and
 worsening psychiatric symptoms?"
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Mac Giollabhui N",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General
 Hospital, Boston, MA, USA; Department of Psychology, Temple University,
 Philadelphia, PA, USA. Electronic address: nmacgiollabhui@mgh.harvard.edu."
          },
          {
            name ml "Foster S",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General
 Hospital, Boston, MA, USA."
          },
          {
            name ml "Lowry CA",
            affil str "Department of Integrative Physiology, University of
 Colorado Boulder, Boulder, CO, USA."
          },
          {
            name ml "Mischoulon D",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General
 Hospital, Boston, MA, USA."
          },
          {
            name ml "Raison CL",
            affil str "School of Human Ecology, University of Wisconsin,
 Madison, Madison, WI, USA; Usona Institute, Fitchberg, WI, USA."
          },
          {
            name ml "Nyer M",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General
 Hospital, Boston, MA, USA."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Brain Behav Immun",
          ml-jta "Brain Behav Immun",
          issn "1090-2139",
          name "Brain, behavior, and immunity"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 7
          },
          volume "103",
          pages "202-204",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 4
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 8
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 10
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 23,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 6,
                day 1,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 22,
                hour 20,
                minute 10
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35452794,
        pii "S0889-1591(22)00108-8",
        doi "10.1016/j.bbi.2022.04.009",
        other {
          db "ELocationID pii",
          tag str "S0889-1591(22)00108-8"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.bbi.2022.04.009"
        }
      }
    },
    mesh {
      {
        term "Central Nervous System"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Interleukin-6"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Mental Disorders",
        qual {
          {
            subh "psychology"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Psychoneuroimmunology"
      },
      {
        term "Receptors, Interleukin-6"
      }
    },
    substance {
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Interleukin-6"
      },
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Receptors, Interleukin-6"
      }
    },
    pmid 35452794,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Review"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35307503,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 3,
      day 21,
      hour 5,
      minute 34
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "A primer on common analytic concerns in psychoneuroimmunology:
 Alternatives and paths forward."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Moriarity DP",
            affil str "Department of Psychology, Temple University, United
 States; Department of Psychiatry, McLean Hospital/Harvard Medical School,
 United States. Electronic address: Daniel.moriarity@temple.edu."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Brain Behav Immun",
          ml-jta "Brain Behav Immun",
          issn "1090-2139",
          name "Brain, behavior, and immunity"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 5
          },
          volume "102",
          pages "338-340",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 29
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 3,
                day 6
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 3,
                day 12
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2023,
                month 5,
                day 1
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 3,
                day 22,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 13,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 3,
                day 21,
                hour 5,
                minute 34
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35307503,
        pii "S0889-1591(22)00075-7",
        doi "10.1016/j.bbi.2022.03.007",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC9004283"
        },
        other {
          db "mid",
          tag str "NIHMS1792717"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID pii",
          tag str "S0889-1591(22)00075-7"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.bbi.2022.03.007"
        }
      }
    },
    mesh {
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Psychoneuroimmunology"
      }
    },
    idnum {
      "F31 MH122116/MH/NIMH NIH HHS"
    },
    pmid 35307503,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Review",
      "Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural",
      "Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35199050,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 2,
      day 24,
      hour 5,
      minute 45
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Disrupting circadian rhythms promotes cancer-induced
 inflammation in mice."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Lawther AJ",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Randwick, New South Wales, 2031, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Phillips AJK",
            affil str "Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, School of
 Psychological Sciences, Monash University, Clayton, VIC, 3800, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Chung NC",
            affil str "Drug Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of
 Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, VIC, 3052, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Chang A",
            affil str "Drug Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of
 Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, VIC, 3052, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Ziegler AI",
            affil str "Drug Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of
 Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, VIC, 3052, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Debs S",
            affil str "Schizophrenia Research Laboratory, Neuroscience
 Research Australia, Randwick, New South Wales, 2031, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Sloan EK",
            affil str "Drug Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of
 Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, VIC, 3052, Australia.;
 Division of Cancer Surgery, Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre, East Melbourne,
 VIC, 3002, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Walker AK",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Randwick, New South Wales, 2031, Australia.; Drug Discovery
 Biology Theme, Monash Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash
 University, Parkville, VIC, 3052, Australia.; School of Psychiatry,
 University of New South Wales, Kensington, NSW, 2033, Australia."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Brain Behav Immun Health",
          ml-jta "Brain Behav Immun Health",
          issn "2666-3546",
          name "Brain, behavior, & immunity - health"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 2,
            day 8
          },
          volume "21",
          pages "100428",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 9,
                day 21
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 7
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 7
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 24,
                hour 5,
                minute 45
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 25,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 25,
                hour 6,
                minute 1
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35199050,
        doi "10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100428",
        pii "S2666-3546(22)00018-7",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8851215"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100428"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Disruption of circadian rhythms occurs in rotating shift-work,
 jetlag, and in individuals with irregular sleep schedules. Circadian
 disruption is known to alter inflammatory responses and impair immune
 function. However, there is limited understanding of how circadian disruption
 modulates cancer-induced inflammation. Inflammation is a hallmark of cancer
 and is linked to worse prognosis and impaired brain function in cancer
 patients. Here, we investigated the effect of circadian disruption on
 cancer-induced inflammation in an orthotopic breast cancer model. Using a
 validated chronic jetlag protocol that advances the light-cycle by 8 h every
 2 days to disrupt circadian rhythms, we found that circadian disruption
 alters cancer-induced inflammation in a tissue-specific manner, increasing
 inflammation in the body and brain while decreasing inflammation within the
 tumor tissue. Circadian disruption did not affect inflammation in mice
 without tumors, suggesting that the impact of circadian disruption may be
 particularly detrimental in the context of underlying inflammatory
 conditions, such as cancer. Importantly, circadian disruption did not affect
 tumor burden, suggesting that increased inflammation was not a result of
 increased cancer progression. Overall, these findings identify the importance
 of healthy circadian rhythms for limiting cancer-induced inflammation.",
    pmid 35199050,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status premedline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35199049,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 2,
      day 24,
      hour 5,
      minute 45
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "The role of yoga in inflammatory markers."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Estevao C",
            affil str "Department of Psychological Medicine, Institute of
 Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, 5 Cutcombe
 Road, Brixton, London, SE5 9RT, UK."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Brain Behav Immun Health",
          ml-jta "Brain Behav Immun Health",
          issn "2666-3546",
          name "Brain, behavior, & immunity - health"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 2,
            day 1
          },
          volume "20",
          pages "100421",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 5,
                day 19
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 20
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 24
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 24,
                hour 5,
                minute 45
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 25,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 25,
                hour 6,
                minute 1
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35199049,
        doi "10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100421",
        pii "S2666-3546(22)00011-4",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8842003"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100421"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Yoga is an ancient system for integrating the mind, body, and
 spirit. In the hatha yoga ashtanga tradition (the eight limb Patanjali Yoga),
 three of the limbs are meditation, breathwork (pranayama) and physical
 postures (asana), which are widely practised in yoga classes. The benefits of
 yoga for mental and physical health are rooted in the practice's origins: in
 yoga, stress is said to be the root of all diseases. The established fields
 of psychoneuroimmunology and immunopsychiatry study the interplay between the
 immune system and mood or mental states. This mini-review has shifted the
 emphasis from research that focuses on yoga's benefits for stress, the most
 commonly studied outcome of yoga research, to a summary of the research on
 the effects of yoga practices on the immune system. The current literature
 bears strong evidence for the benefits of yoga on the levels of circulating
 cortisol and classical inflammatory markers, such as C-reactive protein (CRP)
 and cytokines such as interleukin-1 beta (IL-1beta), interleukin 6 (IL-6),
 tumour necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-alpha) and interferon-gamma (INF-gamma).
 The evidence for other less studied markers, telomerase activity,
 beta-endorphins, Immunoglobulin A (IgA) and brain-derived neurotrophic factor
 (BDNF) is also growing. This mini-review centres around the interplay between
 yoga and these markers in stress management and depression, vascular and
 immune function in the older population, cardiovascular and metabolic
 diseases, auto-immune diseases, breast cancer and pregnancy. Overall, the
 literature examined reveals the novelty of this field of research and sheds
 light on methodological challenges; however, it uncovers the potential for
 yoga to be used as adjuvant therapy in conditions with an inflammatory
 component.",
    pmid 35199049,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status premedline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35130814,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 2,
      day 8,
      hour 5,
      minute 37
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Immunopsychiatry: an update on autoimmune encephalitis for
 neuropsychiatrists."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Marques FMC",
            affil str "Cognitive and Behavioral Neurology, Department of
 Clinical Medicine, Federal University of Goias, School of Medicine, Goiania,
 GO, Brazil."
          },
          {
            name ml "Nardi AE",
            affil str "Institute of Psychiatry, Federal University of Rio de
 Janeiro, School of Medicine, Brazil."
          },
          {
            name ml "Teixeira AL",
            affil str "Neurology and Psychiatry, University of Texas Health
 Science Center McGovern Medical School, Houston, TX, USA."
          },
          {
            name ml "Caixeta L",
            affil str "Neurology and Neuropsychiatry, Department of Clinical
 Medicine, Federal University of Goias, School of Medicine, Goiania, GO,
 Brazil."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Expert Rev Neurother",
          ml-jta "Expert Rev Neurother",
          issn "1744-8360",
          name "Expert review of neurotherapeutics"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 2
          },
          volume "22",
          issue "2",
          pages "155-167",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 9,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 7,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 2,
                day 8,
                hour 5,
                minute 37
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35130814,
        doi "10.1080/14737175.2022.2038136",
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1080/14737175.2022.2038136"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "INTRODUCTION: Autoimmune encephalitis (AIE) is a group of
 immune-mediated inflammatory processes of the brain with marked psychiatric
 features. Although relatively rare, they might offer difficult differential
 diagnosis with psychiatric conditions, especially catatonia and psychotic
 syndromes. Anti-N-methyl-d-aspartate receptor (NMDAR) encephalitis is the
 most common AIE, presenting with psychiatric syndromes in 90% of cases. The
 associated psychopathology is complex, pleomorphic, and best characterized
 when there is involvement of a psychiatrist in the assessment. AREAS COVERED:
 This text will review the main aspects of AIE to psychiatrists and/or
 neuropsychiatrists. EXPERT OPINION: Immune system dysfunction has been
 implicated in the pathophysiology of psychiatric symptoms and disorders. The
 use of diagnostic criteria for possible AIE, especially when specific
 antibodies of AIE are not available, allows early diagnosis and prompt
 treatment which are associated with better clinical outcomes. The study of
 the psychiatric aspects of AIE can broaden our knowledge of the underlying
 mechanisms of various psychiatric manifestations.",
    mesh {
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Anti-N-Methyl-D-Aspartate Receptor Encephalitis",
        qual {
          {
            subh "diagnosis"
          },
          {
            subh "psychology"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Catatonia",
        qual {
          {
            subh "complications"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Hashimoto Disease",
        qual {
          {
            subh "diagnosis"
          },
          {
            subh "psychology"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Mental Disorders",
        qual {
          {
            subh "complications"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Psychiatry"
      },
      {
        term "Receptors, N-Methyl-D-Aspartate"
      }
    },
    substance {
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Receptors, N-Methyl-D-Aspartate"
      }
    },
    pmid 35130814,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 35039006,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2022,
      month 1,
      day 18,
      hour 5,
      minute 34
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "NSAID use and unnatural deaths after cancer diagnosis: a
 nationwide cohort study in Sweden."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Shen Q",
            affil str "Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics,
 Karolinska Institutet, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden. qing.shen@ki.se."
          },
          {
            name ml "Sjolander A",
            affil str "Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics,
 Karolinska Institutet, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Sloan EK",
            affil str "Drug Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of
 Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, VIC, 5052, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Walker AK",
            affil str "Drug Discovery Biology Theme, Monash Institute of
 Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, VIC, 5052, Australia.;
 Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research Australia, Randwick,
 New South Wales, 2031, Australia.; School of Psychiatry, University of New
 South Wales, Sydney, 2052, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Fall K",
            affil str "Unit of Integrative Epidemiology, Institute of
 Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden.;
 Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Medical Sciences, Orebro
 University, SE-701 82, Orebro, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Valdimarsdottir U",
            affil str "Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics,
 Karolinska Institutet, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden.; Center of Public Health
 Sciences, University of Iceland, IS-101, Reykjavik, Iceland.; Department of
 Epidemiology, Harvard T. H. Chan. School of Public Health, Boston, MA, 02115,
 USA."
          },
          {
            name ml "Sparen P",
            affil str "Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics,
 Karolinska Institutet, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Smedby KE",
            affil str "Division of Clinical Epidemiology, Department of
 Medicine Solna, Karolinska Institutet, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden.; Center
 for Hematology, Karolinska University Hospital, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Fang F",
            affil str "Unit of Integrative Epidemiology, Institute of
 Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, SE-171 77, Stockholm, Sweden."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "BMC Cancer",
          ml-jta "BMC Cancer",
          issn "1471-2407",
          name "BMC cancer"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 1,
            day 17
          },
          volume "22",
          issue "1",
          pages "75",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 9,
                day 14
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 12,
                day 15
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 18,
                hour 5,
                minute 34
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 1,
                day 19,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 3,
                day 4,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 35039006,
        doi "10.1186/s12885-021-09120-9",
        pii "10.1186/s12885-021-09120-9",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8764760"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1186/s12885-021-09120-9"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "BACKGROUND: Cancer patients experience increased risk of death
 from accident and suicide. Cognitive impairment induced by cancer-related
 inflammation and stress-related psychiatric symptoms may be underlying
 mechanisms. We therefore studied the association between use of nonsteroidal
 anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) and risk of these outcomes. METHODS:
 Following a cohort of 388,443 cancer patients diagnosed between October 2005
 and December 2014 in Sweden, we ascertained dispense of aspirin or
 non-aspirin NSAIDs from 3 months before cancer diagnosis onward and defined
 the on-medication period as from date of drug dispense until the prescribed
 dosage was consumed. Follow-up time outside medicated periods and time from
 unexposed patients were defined as off-medication periods. We used Cox models
 to estimate hazard ratios (HRs) of death due to suicide or accident, by
 comparing the on-medication periods with off-medication periods. RESULTS: In
 total, 29.7% of the cancer patients had low-dose aspirin dispensed and 29.1%
 had non-aspirin NSAIDs dispensed. Patients with aspirin use were more likely
 to be male than patients without aspirin use. Compared with off-medication
 periods, there was a 22% lower risk of accidental death (N = 651; HR 0.78,
 95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.70 to 0.87) during on-medication periods with
 aspirin. The use of aspirin was not associated with risk of suicide (N = 59;
 HR 0.96, 95% CI: 0.66 to 1.39). No association was noted between use of
 non-aspirin NSAIDs and the risk of suicide (N = 13; HR 0.95, 95% CI: 0.42 to
 2.18) or accidental death (N = 59; HR 0.92, 95% CI: 0.68 to 1.26).
 CONCLUSIONS: Intake of low-dose aspirin after cancer diagnosis was associated
 with a lower risk of unnatural deaths among cancer patients.",
    mesh {
      {
        term "Accidents",
        qual {
          {
            subh "mortality"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Aged"
      },
      {
        term "Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal",
        qual {
          {
            mp TRUE,
            subh "therapeutic use"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Aspirin",
        qual {
          {
            mp TRUE,
            subh "therapeutic use"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Cause of Death"
      },
      {
        term "Drug Prescriptions",
        qual {
          {
            mp TRUE,
            subh "statistics & numerical data"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Female"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        term "Male"
      },
      {
        term "Middle Aged"
      },
      {
        term "Mortality, Premature",
        qual {
          {
            mp TRUE,
            subh "trends"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Neoplasms",
        qual {
          {
            mp TRUE,
            subh "mortality"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Proportional Hazards Models"
      },
      {
        term "Registries"
      },
      {
        term "Suicide",
        qual {
          {
            subh "statistics & numerical data"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Sweden"
      }
    },
    substance {
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal"
      },
      {
        type cas,
        cit "R16CO5Y76E",
        name "Aspirin"
      }
    },
    pmid 35039006,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34921784,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 12,
      day 18,
      hour 20,
      minute 12
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Immunopsychiatry in 2021: premise to promise, and back again."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Al-Diwani A",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry, University of Oxford,
 Warneford Hospital, Oxford OX3 7JX, UK; Oxford Autoimmune Neurology Group,
 Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Oxford, Oxford,
 UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Pillinger T",
            affil str "Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience,
 Department of Psychosis Studies, King's College London, London, UK;
 Psychiatric Imaging Group, MRC London Institute of Medical Sciences,
 Hammersmith Hospital, Imperial College London, London, UK; Institute of
 Clinical Sciences, Faculty of Medicine, Imperial College London, London, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Lennox B",
            affil str "Department of Psychiatry, University of Oxford,
 Warneford Hospital, Oxford OX3 7JX, UK. Electronic address:
 belinda.lennox@psych.ox.ac.uk."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Lancet Psychiatry",
          ml-jta "Lancet Psychiatry",
          issn "2215-0374",
          name "The lancet. Psychiatry"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 1
          },
          volume "9",
          issue "1",
          pages "11-12",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 12
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 18
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 19
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 12,
                day 18,
                hour 20,
                minute 12
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 12,
                day 19,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 12,
                day 29,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34921784,
        pii "S2215-0366(21)00466-1",
        doi "10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00466-1",
        other {
          db "ELocationID pii",
          tag str "S2215-0366(21)00466-1"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00466-1"
        }
      }
    },
    mesh {
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Allergy and Immunology",
        qual {
          {
            subh "trends"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Psychiatry",
        qual {
          {
            subh "trends"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Psychoneuroimmunology",
        qual {
          {
            subh "trends"
          }
        }
      }
    },
    pmid 34921784,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34875343,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 12,
      day 7,
      hour 20,
      minute 13
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Clocking onto chemotherapy to enhance cancer treatment."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Phillips AJK",
            affil str "Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, School of
 Psychological Sciences, Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Lawther AJ",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Randwick, New South Wales 2031, Australia; School of Psychiatry,
 University of New South Wales, Randwick, NSW, Australia."
          },
          {
            name ml "Walker AK",
            affil str "Laboratory of ImmunoPsychiatry, Neuroscience Research
 Australia, Randwick, New South Wales 2031, Australia; School of Psychiatry,
 University of New South Wales, Randwick, NSW, Australia; Drug Discovery
 Biology Theme, Monash Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash
 University, Parkville, VIC, Australia. Electronic address:
 a.walker@neura.edu.au."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Brain Behav Immun",
          ml-jta "Brain Behav Immun",
          issn "1090-2139",
          name "Brain, behavior, and immunity"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 2
          },
          volume "100",
          pages "172-173",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 28
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 29
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 12,
                day 8,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 12,
                day 8,
                hour 6,
                minute 1
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 12,
                day 7,
                hour 20,
                minute 13
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34875343,
        pii "S0889-1591(21)00627-9",
        doi "10.1016/j.bbi.2021.11.024",
        other {
          db "ELocationID pii",
          tag str "S0889-1591(21)00627-9"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.bbi.2021.11.024"
        }
      }
    },
    pmid 34875343,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't"
    },
    status premedline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34801117,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 11,
      day 21,
      hour 20,
      minute 27
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Antipsychotics and COVID-19: the debate goes on - Authors' reply."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "De Picker L",
            affil str "University Psychiatric Hospital Campus Duffel, 2570
 Duffel, Belgium; Collaborative Antwerp Psychiatric Research Institute,
 University of Antwerp, Antwerp, Belgium. Electronic address:
 livia.depicker@uantwerp.be."
          },
          {
            name ml "Mazza MG",
            affil str "Psychiatry & Clinical Psychology, Division of
 Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy;
 University Vita-Salute San Raffaele, Milan, Italy."
          },
          {
            name ml "Vai B",
            affil str "Psychiatry & Clinical Psychology, Division of
 Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy;
 Fondazione Centro San Raffaele, Milan, Italy."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Lancet Psychiatry",
          ml-jta "Lancet Psychiatry",
          issn "2215-0374",
          name "The lancet. Psychiatry"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2021,
            month 12
          },
          volume "8",
          issue "12",
          pages "1030-1031",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 14
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 14
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 21,
                hour 20,
                minute 27
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 22,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 25,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34801117,
        pii "S2215-0366(21)00428-4",
        doi "10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00428-4",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8601685"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID pii",
          tag str "S2215-0366(21)00428-4"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00428-4"
        }
      }
    },
    mesh {
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Antipsychotic Agents"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "COVID-19"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        term "SARS-CoV-2"
      }
    },
    substance {
      {
        type nameonly,
        name "Antipsychotic Agents"
      }
    },
    pmid 34801117,
    pub-type {
      "Letter",
      "Comment"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34778569,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 11,
      day 15,
      hour 7,
      minute 12
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Research priorities for neuroimmunology: identifying the key
 research questions to be addressed by 2030."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "MacKenzie G",
            affil str "Wellcome Trust, London, NW1 2BE, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Subramaniam S",
            affil str "Wellcome Trust, London, NW1 2BE, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Caldwell LJ",
            affil str "Wellcome Trust, London, NW1 2BE, UK.; UK Dementia
 Research Institute Headquarters, London, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Fitzgerald D",
            affil str "Wellcome-Wolfson Institute for Experimental Medicine,
 Queen's University Belfast, Belfast, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Harrison NA",
            affil str "Cardiff University Brain Research Imaging Centre
 (CUBRIC), Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.; Division of Psychological
 Medicine and Clinical Neuroscience, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Hong S",
            affil str "UK Dementia Research Institute, Institute of Neurology,
 University College London, London, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Irani SR",
            affil str "Oxford Autoimmune Neurology Group, Nuffield Department
 of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.; Department of
 Neurology, Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Khandaker GM",
            affil str "MRC integrative Epidemiology Unit, Population Health
 Sciences, Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.; Centre
 for Academic Mental Health, Population Health Sciences, Bristol Medical
 School, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.; Department of Psychiatry,
 University of Cambridge School of Clinical Medicine, University of Cambridge,
 Cambridge, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Liston A",
            affil str "Laboratory of Lymphocyte Signalling and Development,
 The Babraham Institute, Cambridge, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Miron VE",
            affil str "UK Dementia Research Institute at The University of
 Edinburgh, Centre for Discovery Brain Sciences, University of Edinburgh,
 Edinburgh, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Mondelli V",
            affil str "National Institute for Health Research, Mental Health
 Biomedical Research Centre, South London and Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust
 and King's College London, London, UK.; Department of Psychological Medicine,
 Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London,
 London, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Morgan BP",
            affil str "UK Dementia Research Institute, Cardiff University,
 Cardiff, UK.; Systems Immunity Research Institute, Cardiff University,
 Cardiff, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Pariante C",
            affil str "Department of Psychological Medicine, Institute of
 Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Shah DK",
            affil str "Wellcome Trust, London, NW1 2BE, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Taams LS",
            affil str "Centre for Inflammation Biology & Cancer Immunology,
 Department of Inflammation Biology, School of Immunology & Microbial
 Sciences, King's College London, London, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Teeling JL",
            affil str "Biological Sciences, Faculty of Natural and
 Environmental Sciences, University of Southampton, Southampton, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Upthegrove R",
            affil str "Early Intervention Service, Birmingham Womens and
 Children's NHS Foundation Trust, Birmingham, UK.; Institute for Mental
 Health, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Wellcome Open Res",
          ml-jta "Wellcome Open Res",
          issn "2398-502X",
          name "Wellcome open research"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2021,
            month 7,
            day 29
          },
          volume "6",
          pages "194",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 7,
                day 9
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 15,
                hour 7,
                minute 12
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 16,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 11,
                day 16,
                hour 6,
                minute 1
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34778569,
        doi "10.12688/wellcomeopenres.16997.1",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8558843"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.12688/wellcomeopenres.16997.1"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Neuroimmunology in the broadest sense is the study of
 interactions between the nervous and the immune systems. These interactions
 play important roles in health from supporting neural development,
 homeostasis and plasticity to modifying behaviour. Neuroimmunology is
 increasingly recognised as a field with the potential to deliver a
 significant positive impact on human health and treatment for neurological
 and psychiatric disorders. Yet, translation to the clinic is hindered by
 fundamental knowledge gaps on the underlying mechanisms of action or the
 optimal timing of an intervention, and a lack of appropriate tools to
 visualise and modulate both systems. Here we propose ten key disease-agnostic
 research questions that, if addressed, could lead to significant progress
 within neuroimmunology in the short to medium term. We also discuss four
 cross-cutting themes to be considered when addressing each question: i)
 bi-directionality of neuroimmune interactions; ii) the biological context in
 which the questions are addressed (e.g. health vs disease vs across the
 lifespan); iii) tools and technologies required to fully answer the
 questions; and iv) translation into the clinic. We acknowledge that these ten
 questions cannot represent the full breadth of gaps in our understanding;
 rather they focus on areas which, if addressed, may have the most broad and
 immediate impacts. By defining these neuroimmunology priorities, we hope to
 unite existing and future research teams, who can make meaningful progress
 through a collaborative and cross-disciplinary effort.",
    idnum {
      "BB/N003721/1/BB_/Biotechnology and Biological Sciences Research Council",
      "MR/M020827/1/MRC_/Medical Research Council",
      "MR/V007173/1/MRC_/Medical Research Council",
      "MR/V031260/1/MRC_/Medical Research Council"
    },
    pmid 34778569,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status premedline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34668170,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 10,
      day 20,
      hour 6,
      minute 58
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Toward the unity of pathological and exertional fatigue: A
 predictive processing model."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Greenhouse-Tucknott A",
            affil str "Fatigue and Exercise Laboratory, School of Sport and
 Health Sciences, University of Brighton, Brighton, East Sussex, UK.
 A.Greenhouse-Tucknott@brighton.ac.uk."
          },
          {
            name ml "Butterworth JB",
            affil str "Fatigue and Exercise Laboratory, School of Sport and
 Health Sciences, University of Brighton, Brighton, East Sussex, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Wrightson JG",
            affil str "Fatigue and Exercise Laboratory, School of Sport and
 Health Sciences, University of Brighton, Brighton, East Sussex, UK.;
 Department of Clinical Neurosciences, Cumming School of Medicine, University
 of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada."
          },
          {
            name ml "Smeeton NJ",
            affil str "Fatigue and Exercise Laboratory, School of Sport and
 Health Sciences, University of Brighton, Brighton, East Sussex, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Critchley HD",
            affil str "Department of Neuroscience, Brighton and Sussex Medical
 School, University of Sussex, Brighton, UK.; Sussex Partnership NHS
 Foundation Trust, Brighton, UK.; Sackler Centre for Consciousness Science,
 University of Sussex, Falmer, BN1 9RR, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Dekerle J",
            affil str "Fatigue and Exercise Laboratory, School of Sport and
 Health Sciences, University of Brighton, Brighton, East Sussex, UK."
          },
          {
            name ml "Harrison NA",
            affil str "Immunopsychiatry Research Group, Cardiff University,
 Cardiff, UK.; Department of Neuroscience, Brighton and Sussex Medical School,
 University of Sussex, Brighton, UK.; Sussex Partnership NHS Foundation Trust,
 Brighton, UK."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Cogn Affect Behav Neurosci",
          ml-jta "Cogn Affect Behav Neurosci",
          issn "1531-135X",
          name "Cognitive, affective & behavioral neuroscience"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 4
          },
          volume "22",
          issue "2",
          pages "215-228",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 9,
                day 21
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 21,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 8,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 20,
                hour 6,
                minute 58
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34668170,
        doi "10.3758/s13415-021-00958-x",
        pii "10.3758/s13415-021-00958-x",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8983507"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.3758/s13415-021-00958-x"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Fatigue is a common experience in both health and disease. Yet,
 pathological (i.e., prolonged or chronic) and transient (i.e., exertional)
 fatigue symptoms are traditionally considered distinct, compounding a
 separation between interested research fields within the study of fatigue.
 Within the clinical neurosciences, nascent frameworks position pathological
 fatigue as a product of inference derived through hierarchical predictive
 processing. The metacognitive theory of dyshomeostasis (Stephan et al., 2016)
 states that pathological fatigue emerges from the metacognitive mechanism in
 which the detection of persistent mismatches between prior interoceptive
 predictions and ascending sensory evidence (i.e., prediction error) signals
 low evidence for internal generative models, which undermine an agent's
 feeling of mastery over the body and is thus experienced phenomenologically
 as fatigue. Although acute, transient subjective symptoms of exertional
 fatigue have also been associated with increasing interoceptive prediction
 error, the dynamic computations that underlie its development have not been
 clearly defined. Here, drawing on the metacognitive theory of dyshomeostasis,
 we extend this account to offer an explicit description of the development of
 fatigue during extended periods of (physical) exertion. Accordingly, it is
 proposed that a loss of certainty or confidence in control predictions in
 response to persistent detection of prediction error features as a common
 foundation for the conscious experience of both pathological and
 nonpathological fatigue.",
    mesh {
      {
        term "Consciousness"
      },
      {
        term "Emotions"
      },
      {
        term "Fatigue"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Interoception",
        qual {
          {
            subh "physiology"
          }
        }
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Metacognition"
      }
    },
    pmid 34668170,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Review"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34607723,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 10,
      day 5,
      hour 5,
      minute 42
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Monitoring inflammation in psychiatry: Caveats and advice."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "Khalfallah O",
            affil str "Universite Cote d'Azur, Centre National de la Recherche
 Scientifique, Institut de Pharmacologie Moleculaire et Cellulaire, Valbonne,
 France."
          },
          {
            name ml "Barbosa S",
            affil str "Universite Cote d'Azur, Centre National de la Recherche
 Scientifique, Institut de Pharmacologie Moleculaire et Cellulaire, Valbonne,
 France."
          },
          {
            name ml "Martinuzzi E",
            affil str "Universite Cote d'Azur, Centre National de la Recherche
 Scientifique, Institut de Pharmacologie Moleculaire et Cellulaire, Valbonne,
 France."
          },
          {
            name ml "Davidovic L",
            affil str "Universite Cote d'Azur, Centre National de la Recherche
 Scientifique, Institut de Pharmacologie Moleculaire et Cellulaire, Valbonne,
 France."
          },
          {
            name ml "Yolken R",
            affil str "John Hopkins School of Medicine, The John Hopkins
 Hospital, Baltimore, United States."
          },
          {
            name ml "Glaichenhaus N",
            affil str "Universite Cote d'Azur, Centre National de la Recherche
 Scientifique, Institut de Pharmacologie Moleculaire et Cellulaire, Valbonne,
 France. Electronic address: nicolas.glaichenhaus@univ-cotedazur.fr."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Eur Neuropsychopharmacol",
          ml-jta "Eur Neuropsychopharmacol",
          issn "1873-7862",
          name "European neuropsychopharmacology : the journal of the European
 College of Neuropsychopharmacology"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2022,
            month 1
          },
          volume "54",
          pages "126-135",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus ppublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2020,
                month 6,
                day 2
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 9,
                day 1
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 9,
                day 7
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 6,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2022,
                month 4,
                day 12,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 5,
                hour 5,
                minute 42
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34607723,
        pii "S0924-977X(21)00753-7",
        doi "10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.09.003",
        other {
          db "ELocationID pii",
          tag str "S0924-977X(21)00753-7"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.euroneuro.2021.09.003"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Most researchers working in the field of immunopsychiatry would
 agree with the statement that ""severe psychiatric disorders are associated
 with inflammation and more broadly with changes in immune variables"".
 However, as many other fields in biology and medicine, immunopsychiatry
 suffers from a replication crisis characterized by lack of reproducibility.
 In this paper, we will comment on four types of immune variables which have
 been studied in psychiatric disorders: Acute Phase Proteins (AAPs),
 cytokines, lipid mediators of inflammation and immune cell parameters, and
 discuss the rationale for looking at them in blood. We will briefly describe
 the analytical methods that are currently used to measure the levels of these
 biomarkers and comment on overlooked analytical and statistical
 methodological issues that may explain some of the conflicting data reported
 in the literature. Lastly, we will briefly summarize what cross-sectional,
 longitudinal and mendelian randomization studies have brought to our
 understanding of schizophrenia (SZ).",
    mesh {
      {
        term "Cross-Sectional Studies"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        term "Inflammation"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Psychiatry"
      },
      {
        term "Reproducibility of Results"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Schizophrenia"
      }
    },
    pmid 34607723,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34607588,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 10,
      day 5,
      hour 5,
      minute 34
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "Measuring clinical outcomes in children with pediatric
 acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome: data from a 2-5 year follow-up study."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "De Visscher C",
            affil str "Centre for Psychiatry Research, Department of Clinical
 Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.
 caroline.de.visscher@momentpsykologi.se.; Stockholm Health Care Services,
 Region Stockholm, CAP Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113 30, Stockholm,
 Sweden. caroline.de.visscher@momentpsykologi.se.; Moment Psykologi,
 Drottninggatan 99, 113 60, Stockholm, Sweden.
 caroline.de.visscher@momentpsykologi.se."
          },
          {
            name ml "Hesselmark E",
            affil str "Centre for Psychiatry Research, Department of Clinical
 Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.; Stockholm Health
 Care Services, Region Stockholm, CAP Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113
 30, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Rautio D",
            affil str "Centre for Psychiatry Research, Department of Clinical
 Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.; Stockholm Health
 Care Services, Region Stockholm, CAP Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113
 30, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Djupedal IG",
            affil str "Stockholm Health Care Services, Region Stockholm, CAP
 Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113 30, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Silverberg M",
            affil str "Stockholm Health Care Services, Region Stockholm, CAP
 Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113 30, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Nordstrom SI",
            affil str "Centre for Psychiatry Research, Department of Clinical
 Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.; Stockholm Health
 Care Services, Region Stockholm, CAP Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113
 30, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Serlachius E",
            affil str "Centre for Psychiatry Research, Department of Clinical
 Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.; Stockholm Health
 Care Services, Region Stockholm, CAP Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113
 30, Stockholm, Sweden."
          },
          {
            name ml "Mataix-Cols D",
            affil str "Centre for Psychiatry Research, Department of Clinical
 Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.; Stockholm Health
 Care Services, Region Stockholm, CAP Research Center, Gavlegatan 22, SE-113
 30, Stockholm, Sweden."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "BMC Psychiatry",
          ml-jta "BMC Psychiatry",
          issn "1471-244X",
          name "BMC psychiatry"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2021,
            month 10,
            day 4
          },
          volume "21",
          issue "1",
          pages "484",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 4,
                day 29
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 8,
                day 26
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 5,
                hour 5,
                minute 34
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 6,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 26,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34607588,
        doi "10.1186/s12888-021-03450-5",
        pii "10.1186/s12888-021-03450-5",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8488538"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1186/s12888-021-03450-5"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "BACKGROUND: It is unclear how to best measure the complex
 symptom presentation of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome
 (PANS). METHODS: Well-characterized participants of a 2-5 year follow-up
 study (n = 34; 56% male) underwent clinical evaluations and completed scales
 assessing global symptom severity, functional impairment and specific
 psychiatric symptoms. We explored inter-correlations between the measures and
 used intraclass correlation coefficients to evaluate the agreement between
 clinician-, parent- and child ratings of the same constructs. RESULTS:
 Ratings on symptom-specific measures varied largely between participants.
 Agreement between informants was excellent on functional scales,
 fair-to-moderate on global severity scales and mixed on symptom-specific
 scales. Clinician-rated global and functional measures had stronger
 inter-correlations with parent- and child-rated functional measures than with
 symptom-specific measures. CONCLUSIONS: General instruments assessing global
 severity and functioning are well suited for the assessment and follow-up of
 PANS, but should be complemented by symptom-specific scales representative of
 core symptoms.",
    mesh {
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Autoimmune Diseases"
      },
      {
        term "Female"
      },
      {
        term "Follow-Up Studies"
      },
      {
        term "Humans"
      },
      {
        term "Male"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder"
      },
      {
        mp TRUE,
        term "Streptococcal Infections"
      }
    },
    pmid 34607588,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article",
      "Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't"
    },
    status medline
  }
}



Pubmed-entry ::= {
  pmid 34589805,
  medent {
    em std {
      year 2021,
      month 9,
      day 30,
      hour 7,
      minute 21
    },
    cit {
      title {
        name "The future of immunopsychiatry: Three milestones to clinical
 innovation."
      },
      authors {
        names std {
          {
            name ml "De Picker LJ",
            affil str "University Psychiatric Hospital Campus Duffel, Duffel,
 Belgium.; Collaborative Antwerp Psychiatric Research Institute, University of
 Antwerp, Antwerp, Belgium."
          }
        }
      },
      from journal {
        title {
          iso-jta "Brain Behav Immun Health",
          ml-jta "Brain Behav Immun Health",
          issn "2666-3546",
          name "Brain, behavior, & immunity - health"
        },
        imp {
          date std {
            year 2021,
            month 7,
            day 30
          },
          volume "16",
          pages "100314",
          language "eng",
          pubstatus epublish,
          history {
            {
              pubstatus received,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 5,
                day 15
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus revised,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 7,
                day 28
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus accepted,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 7,
                day 28
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus other,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 9,
                day 30,
                hour 7,
                minute 21
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus pubmed,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 1,
                hour 6,
                minute 0
              }
            },
            {
              pubstatus medline,
              date std {
                year 2021,
                month 10,
                day 1,
                hour 6,
                minute 1
              }
            }
          }
        }
      },
      ids {
        pubmed 34589805,
        doi "10.1016/j.bbih.2021.100314",
        pii "S2666-3546(21)00117-4",
        other {
          db "pmc",
          tag str "PMC8474175"
        },
        other {
          db "ELocationID doi",
          tag str "10.1016/j.bbih.2021.100314"
        }
      }
    },
    abstract "Psychoneuroimmunology, the area of research dedicated to
 understanding the fundamental interactions between the central nervous system
 and the immune system, has given rise to the development of Immunopsychiatry,
 a new discipline which harnesses the immune system to produce beneficial
 outcomes for mental health problems. Immunopsychiatry has the potential to
 become a clinically relevant specialty area in psychiatric practice, but has
 not yet been adopted by the wider mental health community. This paper aims to
 map out the future trajectory of Immunopsychiatry on its road towards
 science-to-policy knowledge translation and clinical implementation. Three
 critical milestones which will need to be reached in order for
 Immunopsychiatry to fulfil its promise for clinical innovation are discussed:
 a clear definition of patients who fall within the immunopsychiatric
 continuum; demonstration of well-defined clinical benefit and incorporation
 in clinical guidelines; and convergence with other paradigms in biological
 psychiatry.",
    pmid 34589805,
    pub-type {
      "Journal Article"
    },
    status premedline
  }
}


